欢迎回来，现在是上届凝聚态课程的第16讲
welcome back it's now the 16th lecture
of the condensed matter course when last
我们不再讨论固体的能带结构，特别是
we left off we were talking about band
structure of solids and in particular we
正在考虑将近自由电子模型作为一种理解方法
were thinking about the nearly free
electron model as a way of understanding
乐队结构总结了我们学到的最重要的东西
the band structure a summary of the most
important things we learned is really
这张图片给出的这里，所以你有自由电子抛物线
given by this one picture here so you
have the free electron parabola and due
到周期性的潜能，您可以从布劳恩自身的边界散布到
to the periodic potential you can
scatter from Braun's own boundary to
Burroughs自己的边界，您可以在Brauns自己的边界上打开一个空隙
Burroughs own boundary and you open up a
gap at the Brauns own boundary you can
如果您现在喜欢一件事，也可以在缩小区域方案中查看它
also view it in reduced zone scheme if
you prefer now one thing that's really
在这张图片中重要的是要意识到处于扩展状态的状态
important in this picture is to realize
that states that are in the extended
在第一个青铜器内部的区域方案状态被下推，而
zone scheme states that are inside the
first bronze own are pushed down whereas
第一个铜牌之外的州被推高，所以也许我会写
states that are outside the first bronze
own are pushed up so maybe I'll write
通常在BZ边界内的状态
that generally States
inside inside BZ boundary BZ boundary
下推式推杆和外推式推杆，外推式推杆，离您越近
pushdown and outside are pushed up
outside pushed up and the closer you are
到边界上的青铜，您的能量从自由变为更多
to the bronze on boundary the more your
energy has changed from the free
电子模型，所以让我们看看是否可以采用此原理并了解
electron model so let's see if we can
take this principle and understand what
当我们使用更高的尺寸时，会发生在各种费米表面上
happens to various Fermi surfaces when
we go to higher dimensions so let's
考虑二维正方形格
consider two dimensions a square lattice
所以我们有一个正方形的青铜色自己的正方形熊，我会画一个正方形的青铜色自己的
so we have a square bronze own square
Bruins own I'll draw a square bronze own
这里是平方K等于零在中间这一点是PI
here it is square K equals zero is in
the middle this point over here is PI
在拐角处的PI上方，让我们首先考虑一个电子的情况
over a PI over a at the corner and let's
consider first the case of one electron
每个晶胞，所以这意味着我们应该有一个一半充满青铜自己的一半
per unit cell so that means we should
have a one half filled bronze own half
充满路易斯的乐队或一半充满青铜的乐队，所以在
filled Louis band or a half filled
bronze own so what happens well in the
没有散​​射的潜力，你只有一个不错的费米圆环或费米
absence of scattering potential you just
have a nice Fermi Circle or Fermi
对我来说，在两个维度上都是长矛，我猜它是光盘
for me spear on two dimensions it's a
disc I guess and this is actually a
相当好地表示了许多具有一个的单价材料
fairly good representation of many mono
valent materials materials that have one
每个晶胞中的电子，例如钠，所以这里是二维
electron per unit cell for example
sodium so here's the 2 dimensional
模拟，您只有一块磁盘，正好填满青铜面积的一半
analog you just have a disk filling
exactly half of the area of the bronze
自己的，所以这个圈子应该恰好感觉到那个区域的一半
own so this circle is supposed to feel
exactly half of the area of of that
方形钠是一种BCC材料，因此它是青铜色的，是这种有趣的有线形状
square sodium is a BCC material so it's
bronze own is this funny wired shape
它是树干菱形十二面体或类似的形状，但是
it's a trunk rhombohedral dodecahedron
or some strange shape like that but
里面感觉正好是体积的一半是球形费米表面
inside it feeling exactly half of the
volume is a spherical Fermi surface
告诉我们钠几乎是一个自由电子系统，因为它是费米
which tells us that sodium is nearly a
free electron system because it's Fermi
现在，表面几乎是完美的球形当我们添加更强的表面时会发生什么
surface is almost perfectly spherical
now what happens when we add a stronger
周期性势，我们让周期性势开始移动
periodic potential where we let the
periodic potential start moving around
青铜器中某些州的能量本身很好
the energy of certain states in the
bronz own well what happens is the
在青铜自己的边界附近但青铜自己的边界内的状态得到
states near the bronze own boundary but
inside the bronze own boundary get
降低能量和最接近棕色区域的状态
pushed down in energy and the states
that are closest to the brown zone
边界被压得最大，所以如果您考虑这里的状态，这是
boundary get pushed down the most so if
you consider a state around here this is
非常接近青铜的边界，所以能量被降低了
pretty close to the bronze own boundary
so it's energy is getting pushed down
比这里的状态更多，其能量因此减少得更少
more than this state here whose energy
is getting pushed down less as a result
费米表面要变形，以至于周围有更多状态
the Fermi surface wants to deform in
such a way that more states around here
将要填充，所以它会像这样变形，使得更多的状态
are going to fill so it's gonna sort of
deform like this such that more states
靠近青铜器自身边界的地方正在填充，因为它们被进一步压低
near the bronze own boundary are filling
because they're getting pushed down more
在能量上比那些远离青铜本国边界的州
in energy than the states which are
farther from the bronze own boundary
在这里得到一个费米表面，看起来有点像这样
here so get a Fermi surface that kind of
looks a little bit more like this a
一点点的变形是由于
little bit deformed
due to the shifting around of the
在青铜器中的国家的能量，实际上这就是我们
energies of the states in in the in the
bronze own and in fact that's what we
获得锂，锂又是单价材料，所以它是费米表面
get for lithium which is again a mono
valent material so it's Fermi surface
应该真的填满第一个青铜器本身一半的形状
should really fill half of the first
bronze own again the same shape of the
古铜色本身是一种BCC材料，您可以看到这里的2D模拟画了一点
bronze own is a BCC material and you can
see here's the 2d analog drawn a little
比我在板上画的要好，您可以看到发生了什么事
bit better than I drew on the board and
you can see that what's happened is
基本上是球形的费米表面接近于
where the Fermi surface which is
basically spherical comes close to the
青铜，被拉向青铜
bronze
it's pulled out towards the bronzong
边界，因为那些将接近棕色区域边界的状态具有
boundary because those states which will
close to the brown zone boundary have
比从青铜器走得更远的州，他们的能量下降得更多
been pushed down more in energy than the
states which are further from the bronze
自己的边界，如果周期性的
own boundary it's okay that makes sense
all right now in fact if the periodic
潜力变得非常强大，会发生什么事
potential becomes extremely strong what
can happen is the states right at the
青铜器自身的边界可以被压低到足以使它们降到费米之下
bronze own boundary can be pushed down
so much that they go below the Fermi
在这种情况下，费米表面会变形直到实际接触到
surface in which case the Fermi surface
deforms until it actually touches the
青铜色的边界，您会得到更像这样的东西
bronze own boundary and you get
something that looks more like this and
填充该形状内部的状态，填充该形状外部的状态
the states inside that shape are filled
and the states outside that shape are
空的，这正是材料铜也会发生的情况
empty and that's exactly what happens
with the material copper also a
一价材料实际上是FCC材料，所以它的形状是青铜
monovalent material is actually an FCC
material so the shape of it's a bronze
区域不同，这是我们之前看到的截头八面体形状
zone is different it's this a truncated
octahedral shape that we've seen before
您会看到哦，这是2D图片，比
and you can see that the oh here's the
picture in 2d which is drawn better than
我已经能够在板上绘制，您可以看到费米表面是
I've been able to drawn on the board you
can see that the Fermi surface is
基本球形，大致球形，但正好填满男爵的一半
basically spherical roughly spherical
but and fills exactly half of the barone
区域，因为它是单价的，每个单元电池一个电子应填充一半
zone because it's mono valent and one
electron per unit cell should fill half
第一个棕色区域的区域，但是球体靠近柏林区域的区域
of the first brown zone but where the
sphere comes close to the Berlin zone
边界靠近青铜区边界的状态的能量降低
boundary the states near the bronze zone
boundary get pushed down in energy and
与其他州相比，那些州优先填充
those states preferentially fill
compared to the other states which are
离柏林区域边界更远的地方，在这里被推动
farther from the Berlin zone boundary
which are over here which are pushed
下降得少，这些状态就变成空的，这样就清楚了
down less and those states become empty
so is that clear how the shape of the
费米表面正在变形，所以那是一个
Fermi surface is getting deformed all
right so that's an that's one
让我们考虑另一个有趣的情况，我们有两个
interesting case let's consider another
interesting case where we have two
每个晶胞的电子，所以这里每个晶胞又有两个电子
electrons per unit cell so here two
electrons per unit cell again we have
在没有铜的情况下，这里的青铜拥有者的K现在中间等于零
the bronze own here's K equals zero in
the middle now in the absence of a
周期性的电位，我们应该只将一个费米圆盘作为费米圆盘I
periodic potential again we should just
have a Fermi Circle our Fermi disk I
猜猜它的体积与第一个青铜器本身的体积完全相同
guess whose volume is exactly the same
as the first bronze own so area in this
如果没有周期性电势，则情况与青铜拥有的VZ区域相同
case equals the same as bronze own VZ
area if there's no periodic potential
那当然青铜区也没关系没有时间看
then of course the bronze zone doesn't
doesn't matter there's no period to see
根本不需要注意青铜区，您将获得一个完美的
at all you don't have to pay attention
to bronze zone you just get a perfect a
完美圆如果周期性势很强，那么
perfect circle how
if the periodic potential is strong then
发生的情况是第一个青铜器内部的所有状态都被下推
what happens is all the states inside
the first bronze own are all pushed down
在能源方面，第一个铜牌之外的州的能源被推高，
in energy the states outside the first
bronze own are pushed up in energy and
而不是拥有一个费米圆环，您将获得整个第一
instead of having a Fermi Circle what
you get is you fill the entire first
拥有自己的青铜器，并且清空整个第二个拥有的青铜器，您会得到一个满满的乐队
bronze own and you empty the entire
second bronze own you get a filled band
以及一个空白和一个空白带，空白被打开得如此之多，以至于所有州
and a gap and an empty band the gap
opens up so much that all the states in
第一个青铜器的所有权低于第二个青铜器的所有州
the first bronze own are lower than all
the states in the second bronze own you
得到一个填充带，一个间隙，一个空带，然后得到一个绝缘体，所以这些是
get a filled band a gap an empty band
and you get an insulator so these are
这两种可能性没有周期性的潜力，这是一个完美的循环
the two possibilities with no periodic
potential it's a perfect circle which
您可以查看是否愿意填充其中的第一个青铜器
you can view if you like as filling part
of the first bronze own that's inside
广场和第二个青铜器的一部分在广场外面，带有一个
the square and part of the second bronze
own that's outside of the square with a
强大的周期性潜力青铜器本身的一切能量都被压低
strong periodic potential everything in
the bronze own is pushed down in energy
所以所有的东西都填满了自己的第一个青铜色乐队，然后有一个空白
so everything fills in the first bronze
own filled band then there's a gap
第二个青铜器拥有的一切能量都被推高，因此存在差距
everything the second bronze own is
pushed up in energy so there's a gap
在填充带和空带之间，所以我们有一个绝缘子
between the filled band and the empty
band and so we have an insulator okay so
那是它的最简单的部分，它所发生的更复杂的部分
that's the simple part of it the more
complicated part of it is what happens
当周期性势弱的势或您知道
when the potential where the periodic
potential is weak or you know
在这种情况下，中间中等强
intermediate intermediate ly strong in
that case what happens is it's some of
布里渊（Brillouin）第一区的州或能源消耗下降的地区
the states in the first Brillouin zone
or pushed down in energy and some of the
州和井，它们都被压低了，但是它们只被压低了
states and the well they're all pushed
down but they're only pushed down a
一点点，所以只有一些其他填充，所以那些是最低的
little bit so only some additional ones
fill so the ones that are sort of lowest
能量尚未充满其状态，因此这些状态将开始
in energy that haven't been filled their
states here so these states will start
除了已经填充的州之外，还包括其他一些州
to fill in addition to the states that
were already filled and some of these
除了已经填充的状态外，其他州也将开始填充
states will start to fill in addition to
the states that were already filled some
这些状态在这里等等，将开始填充角落，
of these states up here and so forth and
will start filling in the corners that
我们还没有填写，但如果潜力不足够怎么办
we haven't filled in already but not
what if the potential isn't sufficiently
坚强，我们不会填写整个第一个青铜器，我们会留下几个
strong we won't fill in the entire first
bronze own we'll leave a couple of
角落里的状态是空的，他仍然是空的，仍然是空的，
states in the corners which are empty he
are still empty still empty and the
这些角落里的状态仍然是空的
reason these states in the corners are
the ones that are still empty are
因为这些实际上是第一个中的最高动能状态
仅距离K最远的青铜等于零，因此应该是最后一个
bronze only the farthest from K equals
zero so those should be the last ones to
补充一下，因为它们具有最高的动能，所以必须
fill that because they have a highest
kinetic energy they would have to be
在它们进入费米表面以下之前，最大程度地向下推
pushed down the most before they go
below the Fermi surface similarly in the
第二名青铜器，所有州的能源都被推高
second bronze
all the states are pushed up in energy
保持充满的是那些动能最低的
the ones that remain filled are the ones
with the lowest kinetic energy these
小碎片在这里，其他所有人都倒空，但这些小碎片仍然存在
little slivers here everyone else
empties but these little slivers remains
填充好了，所以现在我有一张图片，它比我能画的更好
filled okay so now I have a picture of
it which is better drawn than I can draw
因此，看起来像这样的东西最早拥有的第一批青铜是
so it will look something like this that
the most of the first bronze own is
填满角落是空的，因为它们是最高的动能
filled the corners are empty because
those are the highest kinetic energy
第一个青铜器拥有的州，第二个青铜器拥有的州大部分是空的，除了
states in the first bronze own most of
the second bronze own is empty except
这些小条仍保留填充，因为它们的动力学最低
these little slivers here which remain
fill because those are lowest kinetic
能量状态，因此最接近K的第二个青铜拥有量等于0，因此
energy states so the closest to K equals
0 in the second bronze own so the this
仍然是金属它仍然具有费米表面这是空的点
is still a metal it still has a Fermi
surface it's a point where the empty
州与青铜器内部的填充状态相遇，所以这里仍然是金属
states meet the filled States within the
bronze own so it's still a metal here
您现在可以进行低能量激发，通常的绘制方法是
you can have low energy excitations now
the way this is typically drawn is to
一次查看每个乐队，或一次查看每个贝林区。
view each band one at a time or each
berlín zone one at a time so you just
画自己的第一个青铜器，你在这里有这张照片，大部分是
draw the first bronze own you have this
picture here it's mostly filled with
只是一些角落仍然空着，第二个青铜器很好，我们将其绘制
just some corners which remain empty and
the second bronze own well we draw it in
缩小区域方案，我们可以将所有内容转换回一个
reduced zone scheme we can sort of
translate everything back to within a
一块青铜，所以这件作品在这里被2 pi转换为在这里
single bronze own so this piece here
gets translated to over here by 2 pi
在这里的这件作品上，并通过2 pi转换到这里
over a this piece here and it's
translated to here by 2 pi over a this
这里的一块被翻译成下面这里的一块被翻译成上面
piece here is translated to down here
this piece here is translated to up
这是通常的缩小区域皮肤，您将所有内容移至
there this is the usual reduced zone
skin you move everything over until it's
都在一个单一的方肌区域内，而且只有这些小部分
all within a single square brawn zone
and it would be only these little
现在可以保留在第二个乐队或第二个青铜乐队中的口袋了
pockets that remain filled in the second
band or the second bronze own ok now
这看起来可能有点不自然，但实际上这正是发生在
this may look a little bit unnatural but
this is in fact exactly what happens in
例如，许多二价材料在每个晶胞中带有两个电子
many divalent materials with two
electrons per unit cell for example
钙，看起来可能有点复杂，但让我一窥
calcium this may look a little
complicated but let me walk you through
这是第二波段中钙的实际费米表面，所以这是
it this is the actual Fermi surface of
calcium in the second band so here's the
这是一种FCC材料，所以它具有截短的八面体形状
it's an FCC material so it has this
truncated octahedral shape here's the
第二本青铜，以简化的石材图样书写，因此看起来完全像
second bronze own written in reduced
stone scheme so it looks exactly like
第一个青铜器自己，你可以看到发生了什么事，
the first bronze own and you can see
that what's going on is there's just
这些仍然充满电子的黄色小区域
these little yellow regions where
electrons are still filled do you be
就像这些小东西偷偷进入第二区一样
there just like these little pieces here
peeking into the the second zone just
小小的帽子将仍然不是很
little little caps will
regions which still haven't quite been
清空后，这些碎片实际上是
emptied and these pieces are actually
the lowest kinetic energy points in the
像这里的这些铜牌一样，第二铜牌实际上是最低的动力学
second bronze own just like these pieces
here were actually the lowest kinetic
第二个青铜拥有的能量点最接近K等于零
energy points in the second bronze own
they were closest to K equals zero
他们处于这些阶段的中心，现在这张照片要难一些
they're in the center of these phases
now this picture is a little bit harder
进行解析，但要查看此处发生的情况透明的地方
to to parse but to see what's going on
here the places which are transparent
费米表面实际上碰到了熊自己边界的地方，
are where the where the Fermi surface is
actually hit the Bruins own boundary and
那是没有画出来，所以这个大孔就是费米表面
then it's it's not drawn so this great
big hole here is where the Fermi surface
电子一直充满直到到达青铜边界
where the electrons fill all the way
until they hit the bronze own boundary
一直没有到青铜器边界的地方
and the places where it's not filled all
the way up to the bronze own boundaries
它被绘制为黄色的位置，所以您在这里看到的这些小角落类似于这些
where it's drawn yellow so you see these
little corners here similar to these
这些边沿的拐角处这些边是最远的点
corners here along these edges these
edges are the points which are farthest
在第一个青铜器中，从K等于零开始，因此如果K等于零，则
from K equals zero in the in the first
bronze own so if K equals zero is in the
中心最靠近的地方都被填满，就像这些被填满
center the places closest are all filled
up just like these are filled up all the
指向最远的青铜边界的方法是沿着这些点
way to the bronze own boundary that
points farthest are the points along
这些边缘，那就是它被涂成黄色的地方
these edges and that's where it's
painted in yellow where the brought
费米表面还没有碰到青铜的边界，让我画一个
where the Fermi surface has not yet hit
the bronze own boundary let me draw it a
那里有点大，实际上含钙，即使它
little bit bigger there there it is so
in fact with calcium even though it's
二价它每个晶胞有两个电子它实际上有两个两个能带
divalent it has two electrons per unit
cell it actually has two two bands which
被部分填充，第一条带被部分填充或大部分被填充
are partially filled the first band is
partially filled or mostly filled in the
第二个带子虽然大部分是空的，但里面仍然有几个电子，所以
second band although mostly empty still
has a couple of electrons in it so it's
实际上是金属的，所以这些都是很多的一般结构
actually metallic okay so these are sort
of the general structure of a lot of
乐队使用了许多材料，因此在本次演讲中
bands in in many many materials so for
the next for this lecture and for a
在接下来的几期讲座中，我们将大量讨论带理论
couple of the next lectures we're going
to talk an awful lot about band theory
以及带理论的后果以及可以推论的物理事物
and the ramifications of band theory and
the physical things that you can deduce
通过考虑带理论来讨论实际材料，并记住我们
about actual materials by thinking about
band theory and remember that what we're
在乐队理论中所做的是我们是否在为每个人都分配能量
doing in band theory is were we're
categorize giving energies to every
青铜器中的晶体波向量本身，我们知道这些晶体波向量
crystal wave vector in the bronz own and
we know that these crystal wave vectors
实际上对应于修改后的平面波或称为Bloch波
actually correspond to modified plane
waves or when a known as Bloch wave
在块定理中起作用，这是描述物理的一个很好的方法
functions in blocks theorem and this is
a very good way to describe the physics
这些材料中的许多都是根据这些修改后的平面波来思考的，但是
and many of these materials thinking in
terms of these modified plane waves but
确实应该警告我们
at
really we should be warned that there
是乐队理论的一些失败，我们现在就讨论其中一些
are some failures of band theory and
we'll discuss some of them now and just
简短地讲一下，然后在这个学期的最后两节课中
briefly and then sort of in the last
couple lectures of the term we'll come
返回并再次讨论其中的一些乐队理论，只是要知道这些
back and talk about some of them again
band theory just to be aware that these
乐队理论的主要失败之一是，尽管有时甚至很少
exist one major failure of band theory
is that sometimes although maybe rarely
单价单价材料单价单元可以是绝缘体
mono valent mono valent materials valent
unit cells can be insulators and
根据乐队理论，这永远不会发生，因为如果你有单声道
according to band theory that should
never happen because if you have a mono
价或三价晶胞，如果每个电子中有奇数个电子
valent or a trivalent unit cell if you
ever have an odd number of electrons per
晶胞也许我应该说一般的奇价中的奇价是任何奇价
unit cell maybe I should say odd valent
in general odd valence any odd valent
一般来讲，在带理论中，单位电池可以是绝缘体
unit cell can be can be insulators in
general in band theory this should never
如果您有一个奇数的单位晶胞，您应该有一个部分充满
happen if you have an odd valent unit
cell you should have a partially filled
乐队，所以应该是金属的，所以我们必须问自己，我们离开了什么
band and so it should be metal so we
have to ask ourselves what did we leave
好了，我们遗漏的是电子之间的相互作用，为什么我的意思是
out well what we left out is interaction
between electrons interaction why i mean
为什么为什么因为我们忽略了而忽略了电子与电子的相互作用
why why because we left out we left out
out electron-electron interaction
电子电子互动如果这些互动很强大，它们可以使
electronic electronic interactions if
these are strong they can make the
即使算上电子，您也会认为绝缘子是绝缘子
material an insulator even though by
counting electrons you would think that
这是一种金属，让我们尝试大致了解为什么会这样，想象一下您拥有
it's a metal let's try to understand
roughly why that is so imagine you have
一排这样排列的原子，并假设它是单价单原子
a bunch of atoms lined up in a row like
this and assume it's mono valent mono
价，所以它是每单位细胞一个电子，但假设相互作用非常
valent so it's one electron per unit
cell but suppose the interaction is very
强假设V库仑B库仑，非常强
strong suppose V Coulomb B Coulomb and
very strong strong
如果库仑的相互作用非常强烈，那么您可能会遇到这种情况
if the Coulomb interaction is extremely
strong then you might have a situation
其中一个原子上不应有两个电子一对一原子上一个原子
where there should be no two electrons
on one atom on one on one atom one atom
所以永远不要在一个原子上找到两个电子，因为库仑
so never should you find two electrons
on one atom because the Coulomb
相互作用会使该能量非常高且非常不利，因此
interaction would make that energy
extremely high and very unfavorable so
如果那是真的，那么你所需要的就是你所拥有的
if that's true
then what you have to have is you have
出现这样的情况，因为每个位置上都有一个电子就可以一个电子
to have a situation where as there's one
electron on every site okay one electron
每个位置一个电子一个电子，那么你问这些
one electron one electron on every
single site then you ask can these
电子会四处移动吗？他们可以从一个位置跳到另一个位置吗？
electrons move around can they hop from
one site to the other well imagine this
试图用一些跳跃矩阵元素T跳到他的邻居肯尼的家伙
guy trying to hop with some hopping
matrix element T to his neighbor Kenny
跳到他的邻居，他不能，因为已经有人坐在那里
hop to his neighbor he can't because
there's someone already sitting there
库仑相互作用阻止您拥有两个电子
and the Coulomb interaction is
preventing you from having two electrons
在一个位置上，由于一个位置上有两个电子，因此具有高能量
on one site high energy from having two
electrons on one site because of the
库仑相互作用，因此您无法跳动，因此有时获得的收益是有效的
Coulomb interaction so you can't hop so
what you get is effectively sometimes
被称为电子交通阻塞，是电子的一种，通常被称为
called a traffic jam of electrons yeah
of electrons more frequently known as a
莫韦尔绝缘体是Nevel Mott的传统蝴蝶结获奖者，他描述了
Mott insulator after Nevel Mott a
traditional bow laureate who described
第一次，大概是为了得到Mott绝缘子
it for the first time and roughly in
order to get a Mott insulator you have
使库仑比跳跃和某种理解更强大
to have the Coulomb much stronger than
the hopping and sort of understanding
为什么还记得电子以形式声明方式跳跃的原因是
what why this is remember the reason
electrons hop in form claim ways is
因为他们可以通过散布波来降低动能
because they can lower their kinetic
energy by spreading out their wave
从一个站点到另一个站点的功能，这是通常的海森堡不确定性，如果
function from one site to another this
is the usual Heisenberg uncertainty if
您可以散布波动函数，您可以知道Delta X Delta P
you can spread out your wave function
you can you know Delta X Delta P you can
降低Delta P，然后可以降低动能，但如果这样
make Delta P lower and then you can make
your kinetic energy lower but if the so
一旦电子由于其扩散而想要形成它
跳到多少能量会降低它在T上的能量
hopping how much does its energy it
lowers its energy about T if it hops
从一个站点到另一个站点（如果允许扩展其波动功能），但是
from one site to another if it's allowed
to spread out its wave wave function but
如果库仑相互作用比跳变强得多，则
if the Coulomb interaction is much much
stronger than the hopping then the
电子会很乐意牺牲它所获得的动能
electron would gladly sacrifice the
amount of kinetic energy it's gaining by
形成波浪以防止自身
forming a
plain wave in order to prevent itself
从坐在一个已经有另一个电子的地方开始
from ever sitting on a site where
there's already another electron in
在这种情况下，您将设置其中之一，这是一张非常经典的照片
which case you'll it will set up one of
these it's a very classical picture of
每个位置只有一个电子，你知道没有量子
just one electron sitting on each site
and you know there's no quantum
必须要考虑力学，它说每个位点都有一个电子，
mechanics has to be considered at all it
says one electron in each site and it's
绝缘子，因为没有人能动，因为没人愿意坐在
an insulator because no one can move
because no one wants to sit on the
邻近站点，因为那里已经有电子，所以这种效应是
neighboring site because there's already
an electron there okay so this effect is
完全没有带理论，所以这是带理论的失败
completely left out of band theory and
so it's kind of a failure of band theory
在课程的最后，我们将再次进行分析
at the very end of the course we'll come
back and analyze this again a second
失败的乐队理论失败到失败的第二个原因是磁性
failure a band Theory failure to failure
number two is magnetism magnetism such
或许我会说我们尚未定义的铁磁
as or maybe I'll say Ferro magnetism
which we haven't defined yet materials
例如铁，其中自旋电子的数量大于
such as iron where the number of up spin
electrons is greater than the number of
电子向下旋转，或者她不等于电子向下旋转的次数
down spin electrons or maybe she's not
equal to the number of down spin
电子可以有不同数量的向上旋转和向下旋转
electrons you can have a different
number of up spin and down spin
电子即使在没有外部磁场的情况下也具有非零磁化强度
electrons a nonzero magnetization even
in the absence of external magnetic
即使当B等于零时
field even when even when B equals zero
外部等于零外部，这永远是不应该的
the external equals zero the external
and this is something that should never
发生在带理论中在带理论中，您应该同时填充向上的电子和
happen in band theory in band theory you
should fill up both the up electrons and
如果电子被充满，则下降的电子将具有相同的费米能
the down electrons to the same fermi
energy if they were filled up
不同地，您可以通过翻转总电子来节省能量，
differently you could save energy by
flipping over sum up electrons and
将它们转变为电子，并平整两个费米表面
turning them into a Down electrons and
leveling out the two Fermi surfaces it
这样做可以节省您动能，原因是
would save you kinetic energy to do this
the reason this happens is something
我们将在课程结束时返回，这也是由于交互作用
we'll come back to at the end of the
course this is also due to interactions
相互作用加上量子力学再加上量子，这完全超出了
interactions plus quantum mechanics plus
quantum and it's totally outside of what
在传统频段理论的基础上，我们将只撤消平面波状态，
will on of traditional band Theory we're
retreating only plane wave States and
向上电子和向下电子的能量应均匀地处理
energies of up electrons and down
electrons should be treated on even
立足好吧，这些就是我们应该放在脑后的事情
footing okay so these are things we
should just keep in the back of our head
乐队理论将失败的地方，但是对于大多数材料，
the places where band theory is going to
fail okay but for most materials we're
考虑禁令理论是思考它的一种很好的方法，所以我们将
think about ban theory is a very good
way to think about it so we're going to
继续使用禁令理论，看看我们能了解多少
go ahead blazed on with ban theory and
see how much we can understand about
用这种乐队理论语言思考材料，所以我们要做的第一件事
materials by thinking in this band
theory language so the first thing we're
在禁令理论中会想到的是光学性质
gonna think about in ban theory is
optical properties optical properties of
固体和固体的结合带理论，所以首先我的意思是
solids solids and bound area by a band
theory so first of all what do I mean by
光学特性我指的是光学特性光学特性
by optical properties what I mean by
optical properties optical properties
表示什么波长的光什么是波长的光
means what wavelengths of light
what wavelengths of light light is
吸收或吸收
absorbed absorbed transmitted or
reflected transmitted or reflected in
换句话说，如果您将材料置于白光下，这通常是
other words if you put your material in
white light which is where we usually
说什么经常反射什么波长的光
put it what is what frequent what
wavelengths of light actually reflect
离开它，进入您的眼睛，给该材料提供您所需要的颜色
off of it and go into your eye and give
that material the color that you
实际看到是为了提醒自己关于可见光的几件事
actually see so to remind ourselves a
couple things about light light visible
您可能还记得的可见光范围是波长范围
light visible light
you might recall ranges from wavelengths
749米，我们一直微红到大约400纳米
of 749 meters which we which is reddish
all the way up to about 400 nanometers
紫罗兰色，这就是您所能看到的或几乎所有人都能以任何速度看到的
which is violet and this is all you can
see or almost people can see at any rate
如果您考虑光子的能量，则约为1.7电子伏特
and if you think about energies of
photons this is about 1.7 electron volt
光子，这是大约3.1电子伏特的光子，介于红色和
photon and this is about 3.1 electron
volt photon and in between red and
紫色是整个彩虹光谱的红色橙色黄色绿色蓝色靛蓝紫色
violet is the whole rainbow spectrum red
orange yellow green blue indigo violet
现在让我们考虑一下平常的事情
the usual thing now let's think about
how it is that light is going to
通过一些禁令理论与我们互动这种类型的光将如何
interact with us with some solid
ban theory how this type of light will
与我们的材料相互作用，所以我们绘制了一些能带图，所以这是一个
interact with our material so we draw
some sort of band diagram so here's a
这是K我不会画整个棕色区域我只是要画草图
here's K I'm not going to draw the whole
brown zone I'm just gonna sort of sketch
一些您知道的图，它将朝所有方向和k空间移动，
some you know diagram this will go off
and to all directions and k space and
也许像这样的图表好，所以这将是一个填充的填充价带，所以
maybe diagram like this okay so this
will be a filled filled valence band so
假设您在这里有一个价带，在价带中我们有一个缺口
imagine you have a filled valence band
here filled valence band we have a gap
间隙II是，然后我们有一个空导带
gap yeah II yep and then we have an
empty conduction band
也许我应该定义我通常所说的E间隙，所以egapp等于min
maybe I should define what I mean by E
gap generally so egapp equals min
导带能量导带能量-最大--最大最大价
conduction band energy conduction band
energy - maximum - - max max valence
波段和能量所以这里的能量和这里的能量之间的差异
band and energy so difference between
this energy here and this energy here so
如果这是一个很大的差距，那是一个绝缘体，如果这是一个很小的差距
if this is a big gap it's an insulator
if it's small gap
这是一种半导体，化学势位于
it's a semiconductor the chemical
potential is somewhere in the middle of
差距，所以现在让我们问可见光将如何相互作用
the gap so when now let's ask how is it
that visible light is going to interact
我们的绝缘子在这里，一些光子会带有一些能量H bar Omega H
with our insulator here well some photon
comes in with some energy H bar Omega H
欧米茄吧，如果光子能量大于间隙，那么它可以激发
bar Omega and if that photon energy is
bigger than the gap then it can excite
从填充价带到空导带的电子
an electron out of the filled valence
band up to the empty conduction band it
吸收电子，并且能量被之间的跃迁吸收
absorbs the electron and that energy is
taken up by the transition between the
低能量状态和高能量状态抱歉，他们说它吸收了
low energy state and the high energy
state sorry they say it absorbs the
电子吸收光子，并从中激发电子
electron absorbs the photon and the
electron it gets excited from
自行车从填充的价带跳到空导
the bike bike jumping up from the filled
valence band up to the empty conduction
乐队，这意味着汤绝缘子随后会出现绝缘子
band so what this means is that an
insulator in soup insulator ensue later
与egapp的间隙大于3.1的Evey是透明的，为什么那么透明
with gap egapp greater then 3.1 evey is
transparent why is that transparent well
如果间隙大于3.1 evey，那么任何光子都可以看到可见光
if the gap is greater than 3.1 evey then
any photon you can see any visible
光子没有能量将电子激发为
photon does not have the energy to
excite an electron to the valent from
价带到导带好，这是光子的关键
the valence band to the conduction band
okay that's the key point if the photon
没有足够的能量来激发两个频带之间的电子
doesn't have enough energy to excite the
electron between the two bands then
基本上，光子根本不能与电子相互作用
basically the photon can't interaction
with the electrons at all the other
光子别无选择，只能完全穿过固体而没有
photon just has no choice but to just go
completely through the solid without
根本不进行交互，因为它无法进行这些转换，因此我们
interacting at all because it can't make
any of these transitions so these we
知道很多这样的材料，其中间隙大于3.1
know plenty of materials like this where
the where the gap is greater than 3.1
令人羡慕，因此尽管它们看起来像透明的钻石石英窗玻璃
evie and therefore they look transparent
diamond quartz window glass although
这不是结晶氧化铝氮化镓，所有这些材料
it's not crystalline alumina gallium
nitride all these materials we which are
透明的，如果您有
transparent they have energy gaps
greater than 3.1 evie now if you have a
较小的带隙较小的间隙较小的egapp然后仅吸收光
smaller band gap smaller gaps smaller
egapp then light is absorbed only
光子只有H-bar Omega大于e间隙的光子才能被吸收
photons only photons with h-bar Omega
greater than e gap can be absorbed can
被吸收，所以一些颜色被吸收，而一些颜色不被吸收，
be absorbed so some colors are absorbed
and some colors are not absorbed and
这为许多材料提供了我们实际看到的颜色，因此
this gives many of the many materials
the colors that we actually see so let
我给你看几个例子，所以这里是你知道我们平时的事
me show you a couple examples so here is
down here is you know our our usual
彩虹，上面写着光子的能量1.7到2.6
rainbow with the energies of the photons
written on them 1.7 evie up to 2.6 that
如果您看一下这种朱砂材料，我们得出的结果约为3.1
we out here is about 3.1 evey if you
look at this material cinnabar it
硫化汞，它的间隙即将消失，这种材料看起来是红色的，因为
mercury sulfide it's gap is about to
evey and this material looks red because
除红色之外的所有其他频率红色的频率足够低
all all frequencies except for red red
has a low enough frequency that it
不能进行任何激发，因此材料是透明的
cannot make any of these excitation so
so that the the material is transparent
变为红色，其频率低于egapp，因此必须通过
to red it's frequency is lower than
egapp so it must go through whereas
其他频率只是被吸收，因此材料看起来是红色的，因为光
other frequencies are just absorbed so
the material looks red because the light
通过该材料是红色所有其他所有其他光
coming through that material is red all
the other all the other light
如果您看一下这种材料，频率已经被吸收了
frequencies have been absorbed if you
look at this material really are it has
间隙稍大2.4在这里一直很好，看起来有点
a slightly larger gap 2.4 evie well all
the way out here and it looks a little
多一点的橙色，因为红色的橙色，黄色的甚至是一些绿色的
bit more orange because the red orange
the yellow and even some of the green
通过材料和所有更高频率的蓝调和
gets through the material and all the
higher frequencies of blues and the
紫罗兰不会穿过吸收的物质，因此实际上结束了
violets do not get through the material
they get absorbed so this actually ends
看起来有点像橙色，现在您可能会说很好，为什么看起来不像
up looking kind of orange now you might
say well how come it doesn't look a
绿色比橙色稍微多一点，但是您有点复杂
little bit more green than orange but
it's a little bit more complicated you
必须对通过的所有这些颜色进行平均，以便
have to sort of average over over all
these colors that get through so the
这些可以穿透的颜色中间大约是橙色，然后
middle of these colors that get through
is somewhere around orange and plus then
可能还有其他影响，但大致原因是看起来是橙色
it can be some other effects going on
but roughly the reason this looks Orange
是因为蓝色和紫色被吸收了
is because the blues and the violets
have been absorbed and the colors that
实际上经历了没有激发和吸收
actually go through without making any
excitations and without getting absorbed
红人和橙子的硫含量差距更大
are the Reds and the oranges
similarly sulphur has an even larger gap
仍然是2.6 CV，现在将您看到的颜色推得更远了
still 2.6 CV and now the the color that
you see is pushed even farther out it
看起来更黄，因为res橙色是黄色，有些绿色和
looks more yellow because the res the
orange is yellow some of the greens and
甚至一点蓝调都通过了这种材料，所以有点
even a little bit of the Blues get
through that material and so it sort of
平均看来有点淡黄的紫罗兰还没有通过
on average looks kind of yellowish the
violets have not gotten through okay
他们已经被吸收了，所以这给许多材料以颜色
that they've been absorbed so this gives
many materials their colors this story
比我告诉你的要复杂一些，因为
is a little bit more complicated than
I've told you because the structure the
波段结构的实际细节对于强度有多重要
actual details of the band structure can
matter a lot as to how strongly
什么东西被吸收或未被吸收，最重要的问题，让我
something is absorbed or not absorbed
and the most important issue and let me
再次绘制这里是我要绘制随机带结构，所以这是一个填充
draw again here is I'm going to draw a
random band structure so here's a filled
价带的一部分，现在您可以进行传导
valence band part of a filled valence
band now you could have a conduction
乐队在这里看起来像这样
band here
it looks kind of like this like that and
因此，您可能会遇到一个可以过渡的情况
so you can have a situation where you
have a where you can make a transition
从这里到这里针对不同的情况，这称为间接过渡
from here to here for different case
this is known as an indirect transition
或间接差距也许我会在这里写下定义，以便
or an indirect gap gap maybe I'll write
down the definition over here so an
间接差距或间接过渡间接差距等于
indirect gap or an indirect transition
indirect gap equals gap between
不同的情况，然后您可以像这样直接过渡
different case and then there you can
have a direct transition like this this
被称为直接间隙直接间隙我也在这里画了直接间隙
is a known as the direct gap direct gap
I've also drawn a direct gap over here
这是同一案例之间的差距直接差距等于同一案例之间的差距
which is a gap between the same case
direct gap equals gap between same case
相同的情况，结果对于交互作用至关重要
same case and it turns out to matter a
whole lot where it's for its interaction
看看差距是直接的还是间接的，让我们思考为什么
with light whether the gap is direct or
indirect and let's think about why why
很好，让我们回想一下，光的光频率是C乘以K，C是
this is well let's recall that light
frequency of light is C times K and C is
巨大的，我们之前就遇到过这个问题，所以如果我们想同时保护这两个问题
huge we've run into this problem before
so if we're trying to conserve both
通过吸收任何合理的光子来吸收光子的能量和动量
energy and momentum by absorbing a
photon the photons for any reasonable
频率不像任何光线频率的X射线频率
frequency that's not like x-ray
frequency for any light frequency if you
把光频率放在这里，k很小，所以当吸收光子时
put in a light frequency here k is tiny
okay so when when a photon is absorbed
如果您要保持动量，请选择电子基本上必须走
the elect if you're conserving momentum
the electron basically has to go
如果光子不携带大量动量，它就不能直线上升
straight up it can't if the the photons
do not carry large amounts of momentum
因为光速如此之大，所以它们只带有很小的动量
they only carry tiny amounts of momentum
because the speed of light is so large
很明显吗？好的，谢谢
is that clear obvious yes okay good
thank you
谢谢你的回答，甚至应该给你一个巧克力，好吗
thank you for answering it should even
give you a chocolate for answering okay
因此，我们所拥有的是直接直接的应用转换
so so what we have is that
direct direct app transitions have
强光吸收强光吸收而间接间隙
strong light absorption strong light
absorption whereas indirect gap
过渡间接过渡的吸收能力很弱，现在您可能
transitions indirect transitions are
very weak absorption now you might
想知道为什么吸收很弱，为什么我们间接吸收了全部吸收
wonder weak absorption why it is we get
any absorption at all with an indirect
差距过渡好吧，您可能会想出一些原因，
gap transition okay there's a couple of
reasons you might think if you have to
如果您无法节省能量或动力，则可以节省能量和动力
conserve energy and momentum if you're
if you can't conserve energy or momentum
根本没有吸收，但实际上有更复杂的方法
there should be no absorption at all but
in fact there's more complicated ways
例如，您可以在其中节省动量能量
where you can conserve energy of
momentum for example you can get one
在光子中，光子进入一个电子激发，再加上一个声子激发，如果
photon in photon in goes to one electron
excited plus 1 phonon excited and if you
这样做，那么电子的动量变化可以抵消电子的动量
do this then the momentum change of the
electron can cancel the momentum of the
声子，您的电子会单向关闭，声子会从
phonon you have the electron going off
one way and the phonon going off the
通过其他方式，您仍然可以节省能量和动力，但这是一个
other way and you can still conserve
both energy and momentum but this is a
流程要复杂得多，发生的情况比平常要少得多
much more complicated process and occurs
much more rarely than just the straight
直接吸收间隙吸收弱的另一种方法是
direct gap absorption another way that
you can get a weak absorption is
不完美动量守恒K不守恒现在为什么
imperfect imperfect momentum
conservation K conservation now why is
您应该保存K只是不完美地记住原因
it that you should conserve K only
imperfectly remember that the reason
我们首先将这个晶体动量K保守起来
that we that K this crystal momentum is
conserved in the first place that all
守恒定律来自对称性，它迫使我们
conservation laws come from symmetries
and the symmetry that it forces us to
有K守恒是由晶格向量平移对称的，因此
have K conservation is translational
symmetry by a lattice vector so that
假设您拥有完美的晶体，那么在打印完美晶体K时
assumes that you have a perfect crystal
so in the printing a perfect crystal K
是绝对保守的，但是如果有障碍
is absolutely conserved but if there's
disorder
来自无序或杂质紊乱或来自无序的杂质，并且
is from from disorder or impurities
disorder or impurities from disorder and
杂质，那么K不再守恒，因为系统
impurities then K is not perfectly
conserved anymore because the system
不再是平移不变的，所以K将不是完美的
isn't translationally invariant anymore
so the K will be not perfectly
保守一点，您会通过间接间隙得到一定程度的吸收，因此
conservative you'll get some amount of
of absorption via the indirect gap so
实际的物理吸收量是能量的函数，所以此处的h-bar Omega
the actual physical absorption as a
function of energy so h-bar Omega here
这里的吸收，这将是一个非常卡通，都像它上的卡通，但
here's absorption this is gonna be a
very cartoon all like cartoon on it but
当您到达间接频率（如果存在）时
when you get to the frequency which is
the indirect frequency if there is an
您知道间接转换频率可能是最低的
indirect transition frequency you know
it could be the case that the lowest
能量激励是直接的，在这种情况下，您知道这只是在您
energy excitation is direct in which
case you know this just occurs when you
当您达到那个频率或更高的频率时
when you get up to that up to that
frequency and at any higher frequency
您会得到这个加其他东西，但是如果间接这样的话
you'll get this plus plus other things
as well but if the indirect like that
如果间接间隙频率较低，请在此处显示
picture there if the indirect gap
frequency is lower
您将在间接频率弱时获得弱吸收，但是当您获得
you'll get weak absorption at the
indirect frequency weak but when you get
最高到直接间隙频率低于间接间隙的直接间隙频率
up to the direct gap frequency direct
gap frequency below the indirect gap
频率，您没有吸收，那么当您达到直接间隙频率时
当您超过此直接间隙频率时，您将获得强大的吸收能力
you get strong absorption when you get
above the this direct gap frequency okay
所以这有点像卡通，吸收是频率的函数
so this is sort of a cartoon the
absorption is a function of frequency
当存在间接差距和直接差距时，让我们来看一下
when there's an indirect gap and a
direct gap so let's actually look at
真实数据真实数据不是很好，但是您实际上可以看到
硅发生了一些间接的变化
little bit what's going on this is
silicon silicon has an indirect gap in a
间接频率小于直接频率的直接间隙
你会看到我像在那儿画画，随着你去，能量正在增加
you can see like I've drawn up there and
the energy is increasing as you go to
左侧，波长随着您向左移动而变小
the left the wavelength is getting
smaller as you go to the left and you
看到随着频率的改变，吸收实际上一直在增加
see that the absorption actually keeps
increasing as you change the frequency
但是当您达到间接差距时，现在会出现一些故障
but when you get to the indirect gap
there's a little bit of a glitch now
这看起来像是一个小故障，但这是对数图，所以如果您将其绘制出来
this looks like a small glitch but it's
a logarithmic plot so if you plot it
线性地，这实际上是一个相当大的一步
linearly it would actually be a fairly
big step
然后它，但它保持增长不断增加越来越多，但
then it but it keeps increasing
increasing increasing increasing but
那么当您达到上限频率时，
then when you get to the
cap frequency there's a really big
再次出现故障，您知道从这里到这里的距离要少十倍，而您
glitch again you know this is more less
a factor of 10 from here to here and you
知道，所以当您达到直接间隙频率时，您将迈出一大步
know so you get a big step when you get
to the direct gap frequency there's lots
其他使您在其他任何地方都难以吸收的过程
of other processes that give you weak
absorption everywhere else more
涉及声子和凌空其他东西的复杂过程，所以它是
complicated processes involving phonons
and volleying other stuff too so it's
不像我在这里很形象地画出的那样简单，但至少您能
not quite as simple as I've drawn here
very figuratively but at least you get
那两个物理的基本概念还可以，所以物理和
the general idea of the those two pieces
of physics okay so the physics and in
您可能已经在EMM课程中学习过一些金属的金属
metals you've studied metals a little
bit before probably in your EMM courses
他们显得有光泽和反光，他们害怕出现光泽和反光的原因
they appear shiny and reflective and the
reason they fear appear shiny and
反射性是因为它们具有高电导率和高电导率
reflective is because they have high
conductivity high conductivity and I
认为您可能是在电磁学课程中用金属研究的
think you probably studied this in your
electromagnetism course by metals
反映您是否这样做，是的，是的，希望是的，所以真的
reflect did you do that yes yes
hopefully yeah okay so really what
您要问的是电导率是Omega的函数，从中
you're asking about is the conductivity
as a function of Omega and from that you
可以得到光学特性光学特性，但再次您知道我们有
can get optical properties optical
properties but again you know we have if
让我画一下，这里有一些青铜，这是金属。
let me draw you have some bronze on here
here's here's a metal metal is a
半填充带，所以我们现在可能会有这样的金属
half-filled band so we might have a
metal like this now the optical
高频的特性很大程度上取决于第二个频段的位置
properties that some high-frequency will
depend a lot on where the second band is
如果您可以过渡到第二个频段，从而改变的西格玛
if you can make transitions up to a
second band that will change Sigma of
欧米茄（Omega）即使在低频下也可能是很好的金属，
Omega even though at low frequency this
thing may be a very good metal and the
如果您正在考虑电子，电子将非常自由地移动
electrons will move very freely if
you're thinking about the the
高频下的电导率确实要担心
conductivity at high frequency you do
have to worry about whether the
过渡与带间过渡对齐，或者不与
transition lines up with an inter band
transition or it doesn't line up with an
带内过渡，无论是否可以进行这些过渡，
intra band transition whether you can
make these transitions or not will
影响光学性能，实际上是详细的波段
affect the optical properties and it's
it's actually the detailed band
使您知道铜看起来像铜或金，金和银的结构
structure that makes you know copper
look copper or gold with gold and silver
看起来与银色有关，可以在两个频段之间进行过渡
look silver it has to do with which
transitions can be made in between bands
在这些不同的材料中，现在不再赘述
in in those different materials won't go
into that in too much more detail now in
这些材料中的任何一个，认识到细节总是很重要的
any of these materials it's always
important to realize that details
光学性能问题实际上对许多事情都很重要，所以我会
a matter for optical properties actually
details matter for many things so I'll
只是写下细节很重要，所以是一般原则
just write that down
details matter um so a general principle
一个人住很重要的细节是当你看着一个表面时
to live by one one detail that matters a
lot is the surface when you look at a
看到材料的表面，并且经常看到表面
material you see the surface of the
material and very frequently the surface
由于某种原因，该材料的材料与其他材料不同，或者
of the material is not like the rest of
the material for some one reason or
另一个非常好的例子是钠这样的材料
another a really good example of that is
a material like sodium sodium is a
真的是很好的金属，但是如果您看一下它的表面，那是一大块钠
really good metal but if you look at its
surface here's a chunk of sodium and the
钠的表面看起来是灰色的，不能反射，为什么很好
surface of sodium looks kind of grey
it's not reflective why is that well
因为你实际上不是在看钠，而是在看氧化钠
because you're not actually looking at
sodium you're looking at sodium oxide
您将钠放在桌子上约一小时之内
you put the sodium out on the table
within about an hour the oxygen in the
空气侵蚀了钠的表面，形成氧化钠
air has attacked the surface of the
sodium is formed sodium oxide sodium
氧化物是绝缘体，所以您实际上看到的是绝缘层
oxide is an insulator so you're actually
seeing an insula a thin layer of
这张图的表面上的绝缘子钠已被切成两半打开
insulator on the surface in this picture
the sodium has been cut in half to open
在金属表面上，因此大约一个小时后，该表面看起来会变成金属
up a metallic surface and so for about
an hour that surface will look metallic
一个小时后，它将再次看起来很棒，因为您正在形成
and then after an hour it will look
great again because you're forming an
上面有一层氧化层，所以表面经常有很多东西
oxide layer on top of it so the surface
is matter an awful lot frequently the
表面不像其他材料
surfaces are not like the rest of the
material
另一个很重要的问题是杂质，我们将讨论
another thing that matters an awful lot
is impurities and we'll discuss
在下一堂课中也会有很多杂质，我将在本堂课结束时
impurities a lot in next lecture as well
I'm gonna be at the end of this lecture
如果有时间，但考虑到光学特性，可以想象我们还可以
if we have time but for the optical
properties let's imagine we have okay
这是一个空的导带空的导带，然后我们有
here's a empty conduction band empty
conduction band and then here we have
一些填充价带填充价带，这就是我们的
some filled valence band filled valence
band and that's what the the our
如果没有杂质，绝缘子或半导体看起来就像
insulator or semiconductor would look
like in the absence of impurities but if
我在材料中添加了一些外来杂质，它实际上可以添加本征态
I add some foreign impurities into the
material it can actually add eigenstates
在间隙中间的能量在
in the middle of the gap at energies
that are somewhere in the middle of the
间隙，所以这些是杂质本征态
gap so these are impurity eigenstates
鸡蛋由于杂质的存在而没有那些
eggs due to the presence of the
impurities in the absence of those
杂质如果间隙较大，该材料可能是透明的，但是当
impurities this material might be
transparent if it has a big gap but when
杂质就可以使一些
the impurities are
then you can make some a number of
某个频率的跃迁直至背面的杂质，这样您就可以获得
transitions of some frequency up to the
impurity in back so that you can get
某些颜色某些颜色有点你知道修改
certain colors sort of certain colors
sort of a you know modifying the
您材料的透明度，因此即使数量很少，
transparency of your of your material so
even with a weak very small number of
杂质会产生很大的不同，所以这是一个经典的例子
impurities this can make a huge
difference so here's a classic example
作为每个人都熟悉的材料钻石，
as the material diamond that everyone's
familiar with it's the diamonds are a
女孩的最好的朋友，或者不是詹姆士·邦德电影或
girl's best friend or whatever the
phrases wasn't that James Bond movie or
无论如何，钻石永远是球队的蒙大拿州
something anyway diamonds are forever
what was the team's Montana in their
钱，所以对于钻石来说，纯钻石是完全清楚的，而如果您
money so so with diamonds pure diamond
is a is completely clear whereas if you
仅添加几个杂质这就是一千万硼杂质
add just a couple of impurities this is
one boron impurity for ten million
碳原子，使钻石有点蓝，这是一个相当著名的
carbon atoms and it turns the diamond
somewhat blue this is a rather famous
蓝色钻石，它是希望钻石的估计价值2.5亿美元
blue diamond it's the Hope Diamond
estimated value of 250 million dollars
它坐在华盛顿的史密森博物馆中
it's sitting in the Smithsonian Museum
in Washington it's also supposed to have
与之相关的诅咒，所以不要去尝试去窃取，这对你非常不利
a curse associated with it so don't go
try to steal it that's very bad for you
或者如果您每百万个碳原子增加一个氮原子
or something anyway if you if you add a
nitrogen atom per 1 million carbons it
使钻石变黄，这是蒂芙尼（Tiffany）钻石
turns the diamond a rather yellow color
this is the Tiffany diamond also highly
蒂芙尼公司拥有的贵重物品，我相信它在新店里
valuable owned by the Tiffany company
and I believe it's in their store in New
约克（York）的估计价值很好，现在可能已经超过1200万
York estimated value well it's probably
a lot more than 12 million now it's a
相当大的美丽钻石，它完全变成了钻石的颜色
rather large beautiful diamond and it's
coming entirely the color of the diamond
并不完全来自杂质，这些钻石实际上是
isn't coming entirely from impurities
now these these diamonds were actually
开采他们是从地雷里挖出来的，但实际上
mined they were done dug out of the
ground out of out of mines but in fact
现代人非常擅长于合成材料
in the modern era were very good at at
making materials synthetically in
实验室，您可以制造出完美无杂质的钻石
laboratories you can make a perfectly
good diamond with no impurities
无论您的实验室中有什么被称为合成钻石，它们都是
whatsoever in your laboratory there's
known as synthetic diamonds they're a
比从地下开采便宜得多，如果您希望它是蓝色的，
lot cheaper than mining them out of the
ground and if you want it to be blue you
如果想要变成黄色，只需添加硼，如果想要，则添加氮气
just add boron if you want it to be
yellow you add nitrogen if you want to
可以是其他一些颜色您可以将其制成粉红色您可以将其制成
be some other colors you can you can
make it pink you can make it you make it
通过添加适当的杂质将其放入您想要的任何颜色
whatever color you want by adding the
appropriate impurities that put it in
正确的杂质本征，合成钻石的优点是
the right impurity eigenstates the
advantage of the synthetic diamonds are
好吧，它们更便宜，实际上它们更多，那里更少
well they're cheaper they're actually
more there have fewer
您可以设计杂质，可以将所需的任何杂质放入其中
you can design the impurities you can
put whatever impurity you want in it you
可以将杂质排除在外，因此它可以像您想要的那样纯净，事实上，如果您
can keep the impurities out so it can be
as pure as you want and in fact you if
您购买人造钻石不支持非洲的任何战争，因此，如果您
you buy synthetic diamonds you do not
support any wars in Africa so if you're
如果您打算购买钻石，请知道
out if you're planning on buying
diamonds you know please you know
他们有一些钻石行业希望您相信的
there's some how they the diamond
industry wants you to believe that
合成钻石在某种程度上不如天然钻石
somehow the synthetic diamonds are
inferior to the to the natural diamonds
从矿山挖出来完全是不对的，它是相同的碳
dug out of a mine it's totally not true
it's the same carbon
实际上，您在实验室中生长的碳可能比
in fact the carbon that you grow in your
lab is probably a lot purer than the
你从地雷里拉出来的东西，所以买人造钻石我
stuff you pull out of pull out of the
mines so so buy synthetic diamonds I
不拥有股票，并说它在钻石内部，但我没有完全披露
don't own stock and said it's inside of
diamonds but full disclosure I don't
好吧，让我们继续讨论一下一旦您
okay so let's go on and start talking
about what happens once you once you
在材料中激发电子，所以这里再次有能量
make excitations of electrons in
material so so again here's energy we'll
绘制一个顶部这里是价带顶部价带顶部
draw the top of a here's the top of the
valence band filled valence band top of
价带价带已填充，并且我已绘制了扣除带的底部
valence band valence band filled and the
bottom of a deduction band I've drawn
这是直接的差距材料，但可能是间接的，并不是那么关键
this as a direct gap material but it
could be indirect it's not so so crucial
而且它仍然是空传导，所以在其中有一些能隙
and it's empty conduction anyway okay
and so there's some gap energy in
两者之间，如果我放入光子以激发电子
between the two and if I put in a photon
in order to excite an electron out of
从价带到导带I的导带然后得到
the conduction band out of the valence
band to the conduction band I then get a
电子在导带中上升，但是我没有电子下降
electron up here in the conduction band
but I get the absence of electron down
在价带中，有一个重要的名字
here in the valence band and that is an
important thing to have a name for which
被称为空穴，也是良好的电子不带电子的名称
is known as a hole also the name of a
good rock band absence of of electron
电子否则被填充
electron in otherwise wise filled
价带，所以当你把这种能量激发电子到
valence band so when you're putting this
energy to excite the electron up to the
导带可能是光子，也可能实际上是热能
conduction band it could be photon or it
could be actually thermal energy to can
如果间隙足够小，那么激发，那么您的温度就足够高了
excite if the gap is small enough so
then your temperature is high enough you
可以从价带到导带热激发电子
can thermally excited electron from the
valence band up to the conduction band
然后你要做的是实际上是在一个空穴对中产生了一个电子
then what you've done is you actually
pair created an electron in a hole
它完全类似于正电子类似拓扑类似
it's entirely analogous to a positron
analogous topology analogous analogous
正电子，我们在外层空间，你知道在外层空间的真空中，如果你
to positron we're in outer space you
know in the vacuum of outer space if you
放入足够高频率的光子，您可以配对创建一个
put in a high enough frequency photon
you could pair create an
您必须将两个MC平方能量放入电子-正电子对中
electron-positron pair you'd have to put
in the two MC squared energy the mass
电子和正电子的能量，您可以创建它们，并且需要一些时间
energy of the electron and the positron
you could create them and is some time
以后电子和正电子可以一起回到并pair灭
later the electron and the positron can
come back together and pair annihilation
发出一个光子是两个光子，可能是同一件事
emit a photon are two photons is a case
maybe it's the same thing here you have
放入间隙能量，然后配对产生一个电子和一个空穴，这些
to put in the gap energy and you pair
create an electron and a hole and these
事物在导带或价带中运行，
things run around in the in the
conduction band or the valence band and
过了一段时间之后，他们可以聚在一起并散发出能量，
it's some time later they can come back
together and emit their energy and
光子或其他方式可以摆脱能量，它们来
photons or in some other way they can
get rid of their energy and they come
回来，他们走过八巷，所以完全类似于
back and they rien aisle eight so it's
entirely analogous to the idea of an
实际上，当狄拉克写下他的正电子理论时，电子正电子对
electron-positron pair in fact when
Dirac wrote down his theory of positrons
他非常了解半导体的发展，并且正在使用它
he was well aware of what was going on
in semiconductors and he was using this
作为或多或少的正电子模型的模型，所以这是一种方法
as as more or less a model of the
picture of positrons so this is one way
你可以安排在价带或电子中得到空穴
you can have you can arrange to get
holes in the valence band or electrons
通过添加光能或
in the conduction band by adding energy
either either a light energy or or
热能激发某人从价带进入传导
thermal energy to excite someone up from
the valence band into the conduction
带，还有另一种方法可以使价带和电子中出现空穴
band there's another way you could get
holes in your valence band and electrons
在您的导带中，使导带重叠，看看我是否画了
in your conduction band which is to get
the bands to overlap see if I've drawn
这个权利，所以如果这两个价带重叠一个
this right so here's my otherwise filled
valence band if the bands overlap by a
一点这里的EF，然后这些状态将被填充在价带中
little bit here's EF then these states
will be filled in the valence band
但价带顶部的状态将不满足并填充最低的
but the states on the top of the valence
band will unfill and fill the lowest
状态在导带中，这正是我们在
states in the conduction band and this
is exactly what we saw in the case of
今天早些时候的最低波段的钙还不够
calcium earlier today that the the
lowest band sort of is not quite filled
第二个频段才刚刚开始填充，所以这变得有点
and the second band is just starting to
fill and so this becomes a little bit
金属的，因为您在价带中有一些空穴，并且在其中有一些电子
metallic because you have some holes in
the valence band and some electrons in
导带现在实际上是一些有用的Naaman粘土chur，
the conduction band now actually some
useful Naaman clay chur which is the
系统中空穴的密度阱的密度可能是电子的密度
density of holes in a system density of
well maybe density of electrons
导带中的电子通常称为N和
electrons in conduction band in
conduction band is usually called N and
它被称为n实际上是因为它不是数字，而是负电荷
it's called n actually for it not for a
number but for negative charge and for
负是电子带负电荷，而空穴的密度
negative is the electrons have negative
charge whereas the density of holes
价带中空穴的密度等于通常带正电荷的PP
density of holes in valence band equals
P P for positive charge that's the usual
Naaman klaich ur以及我们是否在导带中产生电子
Naaman klaich ur and whether we create
our electrons in the conduction band in
通过添加这样的能量或通过重叠
our holes in our valence band by adding
energy like this or by overlapping the
乐队看起来像N等于P所以也许我们
band's like that
it appears that N equals P so maybe we
写下n通常等于P，因为它是
write that down
does n equal P generally because it's
每次我创建电子时，我都会创建一个洞，并在这张照片中
every time I created an electron I
created a hole and in that picture up
每当我将一个电子从一个带转移到另一个带时，
there every time I transferred one
electron from one band to the other I
在导带中产生电子，在价带中产生空穴
created both electron in the conduction
band and a hole in the valence band so
看起来答案是肯定的，但是有点像合格的
it looks like the answer is yes but it's
going to be sort of a qualified yes yes
如果是纯材料，否，否，我们有杂质，因此我们必须进行分类
if in pure material no
No we have impurities so we have to sort
考虑一下杂质如何改变这里的故事，所以让我们考虑
of think about how it is that impurities
change the story here so let's consider
世界上最重要的半导体硅是所有电子产品
the world's most important semiconductor
silicon silicon is what all electronics
或多或少是由制成的，所以我将其绘制为方格
more or less are made out of so I'm
going to draw it as a square lattice
即使它不是正方形晶格，也有FCC晶格，但是
even though it's not a square lattice is
an FCC lattice with the basis but this
只是出于比喻的目的，在这里将它们绘制为方格
will just for figurative purposes will
draw it as a square lattice here these
都是硅原子，那么我们将想象一个硅原子
are all silicon atoms then we're going
to imagine taking one silicon atom and
用另一个原子替换它我们将使用哪个原子
replacing it with another atom which
atom are we going to use we'll use
元素周期表上硅旁边的东西
something right next to silicon on the
periodic table
你现在要摄取磷吗，所以我们将这个原子带入这里
will you take phosphorus now so we'll
take this atom here and make it into a
磷原子化石我要写出化石，以免与P混淆
phosphorus atom foss I'm gonna write out
foss so it doesn't get confused with P
不幸的是磷的符号是P，P也是符号
it's unfortunate that the symbol for
phosphorus is P and P is also the symbol
对于不相关的孔的密度，只是随机发生
for the density of holes that are
unrelated just sort of random happens to
不方便，但是我们必须处理它，因此磷等于
be inconvenient but we have to deal with
it so phosphorus equals it's basically
它是硅原子加一个质子，在左边，在硅的右边
it's a silicon atom plus one proton it's
on the Left it's on the right of silicon
在周期表中加一个电子加一个电子，它有一些中子
in the periodic table plus one electron
plus one electron it has some neutrons
我们不太担心，所以我可以服用这种磷并查看它
to which we're not so concerned about so
I can take this phosphorus and view it
作为硅加上额外的正电荷加上一个额外的电子就可以了
as a silicon plus an additional positive
charge plus one additional electron okay
所以它在这里有一个额外的正电荷，那里有一个电子
so it has an additional positive charge
here and one electron sitting up there
1e现在坐在别处，那个电子会发生什么
1e sitting somewhere else now what
happens to that one electron this one
另外，也许我应该先谈一下质子，以便这个质子转
addition well maybe I should talk about
the proton first so this proton turns
并在下一堂课中证明这一点，您可以或多或少忽略
out and will justify this in the next
lecture you can more or less ignore the
那个质子的存在，只是将其视为硅核，是的
presence of that proton and just think
of it as a silicon nucleus yes it has a
收费，但收费并不重要，重要的是
charge but that charge is not so
important what's important is this
电子在这里进行的很好，价带已经充满
electron here where does it go well the
valence band is already filled we
从硅开始，它有一个填充的价带纯硅有一个填充
started with silicon it had a filled
valence band pure silicon has a filled
价带和一个间隙，然后是一个空的导带，所以这个一个电子
valence band and a gap and then an empty
conduction band so this one electron
必须进入传导浴，所以在这里
must go
into conduction bath so here we have
在导带中添加了一个电子，而没有在
added an electron into the conduction
band without adding a hole into the
价带我让我给你看一个更好的动画片
valence band let me let me show you a
better cartoon of this so in this
图片中的电子被绘制成围绕硅原子的小圆圈
picture the electrons are drawn as
little circles around the silicon atom
并且假设有两个电子彼此相邻的事实
and the fact that there are two
electrons next to each other is supposed
描绘将其与硅原子结合在一起的共价键，
to depict a covalent bond that holds it
to silicon atoms together the fact that
除了磷在哪里，所有电子都是
all you know everywhere except for where
the phosphorous is all the electrons are
绑在这些共价键上的另一种说法是，我们有一个
tied up in these covalent bonds is
another way of saying that we have a
填充带占所有电子，并且存在一个缺口
filled band all the electrons are
accounted for and there's a gap to
现在将电子放到磷中时，将电子放到其他地方
putting the electrons anywhere else now
when you put it in the phosphorus the
磷可以形成四个相同的四个共价键，但其中有一个
phosphorus can make the four same four
covalent bonds but then there's one
剩下的电子，由于整个价带被填满
electron left over and since the entire
valence band is filled the only place
电子可以进入到导带中，所以这就是
that electron can go is up into the
conduction band okay so that's what
碰巧你可以用不同的掺杂剂做相同的游戏
happens you can do the same play the
same game you with a different dopant
让我们备份到硅另一侧的掺杂剂是铝，我们可以使用
let's back up to dopants on the other
side of silicon is aluminum we could use
铝铝是硅-一个质子，我们再也不用担心
aluminum aluminum which is silicon - one
proton and again we don't have to worry
关于质子太多，我们可以忽略这一点，这将证明以后忽略并
about the proton too much we can ignore
this will justify that later ignore and
那么它是负一电子，所以铝会丢失一个电子
then it's minus one electron so with
aluminium we're missing one electron
我们需要填充价带，所以这增加了一个整体，增加了一个整体
that we need to fill the valence band so
this adds a whole adds whole as a whole
实际上让我在这里画得很好，使用硼而不是铝硼是
and actually let me draw it okay here
that using boron not aluminum boron is
在元素周期表中铝的正上方，因此化学上
right above aluminum in the periodic
table so it's chemically exactly the
一样的故事硼是三价的，它可以使三价共价
same so it's the same story boron is
trivalent it can make three covalent
键，但是为了填充整个价带，缺少一个电子
bonds but there's one electron missing
in order to fill the entire valence band
所以我们缺少一个电子，让我只给出几个名词
so we're missing one electron let me
just give a couple terms of nominal
艾希尔对不起，我要结束了，所以磷被称为已知
Eicher I'm sorry I'm going over before
we end so phosphorus is known as a known
作为掺杂物，因为它会增加N姨妈
as a in dopant
because it adds an N aunt a negative
电荷或施主杂质或施主杂质，因为它提供电子
charge or a donor impurity or donor
impurity because it donates an electron
而铝或硼被称为P掺杂剂，因为它会增加一个孔或一个
whereas aluminum or boron is known as as
P dopant because it adds a hole or an
受主杂质，因为它接受或受主杂质SEP额外的电子
acceptor impurity because it accepts or
acceptor impurity SEPs an extra electron
也许我应该在结束之前定义open一词，所以dopant dopant是
and maybe I should define the word
opened before ending so dopant dopant is
泛指引入的外国化学品
a general word which means the a foreign
chemical foreign chemical introduced
引入纯净的化合物中
introduced into an otherwise pure to
otherwise pure compound otherwise pure
纯物质如此纯净的物质我想改变它的性质来改变
pure material so a pure substance I
guess to change its properties to change
如今，它的属性相当笼统
its properties rather general word
particular importance these days
考虑到奥运会正在进行中，所以我想我们会在那儿结束，
considering the Olympics are going on
okay so I guess we'll end there and
明天我们会再次开始，抱歉
we'll start again tomorrow sorry for
going over
[掌声]
[Applause]